{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "There ______ no rule about the movement of traffic before the Pope came to visit Paris.",
      "a": "is",
      "b": "are",
      "c": "was",
      "d": "were",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "- There + be (is/are/was/were/have been/had been/ will be) used to say that something exists or happens\n\n+When the following noun is plural, use ‘there are/were/have been/will be'\n\n+When the following noun is singular countable/uncountable, use ‘there is/was/has been/will be'\n\n- We fill the blank with 'there was' (simple past) to make it consistent with tense of 'came' (simple past)\n\n(Verb Tense Consistency\n\n-Verb tense consistency on the sentence level:\n\n+Keep tenses consistent within sentences. \n\n+Do not change tenses when there is no time change for the action.\n\n-Verb tense consistency on the paragraph level:\n\n+Generally, establish a primary tense and keep tenses consistent from sentence to sentence. \n\n+Do not shift tenses between sentences unless there is a time change that must be shown.)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was there in your cup?' 'There _____ two things.",
      "a": "was",
      "b": "were",
      "c": "had",
      "d": "have",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "- There is (= have): used when object is singular or uncountable noun\n- There are (= have): used when object is plural noun\n- Past simple : there is -> there was; there are -> there were",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "If there _________gravity, water wouldn't run downhill.",
      "a": "was",
      "b": "is",
      "c": "were",
      "d": "are",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "-If clause type 2:\n\n+The type 2 conditional refers to an unlikely or hypothetical condition and its probable result. These sentences are not based on the actual situation. In type 2 conditional sentences, the time is now or any time and the situation is hypothetical.\n\n+Form: if + Simple Past, Conditional I (= would + Infinitive)\n\n+ Verb “to be”: “were” is used instead of “was” (Ex: If I were you, I would….)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "When he finished, there ________ only two pieces of cake left.",
      "a": "is",
      "b": "was",
      "c": "are",
      "d": "were",
      "answer": "4",
      "explain": "- Put verb in simple past tense to tell about series of action happened in past.",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "There ____ any sugar in the jar.",
      "a": "isn't",
      "b": "aren't",
      "c": "is",
      "d": "are",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "- There is/ there are: used to say that something exists or happens\n\n+When the following noun is plural, use ‘there are’\n\n+When the following noun is singular countable/uncountable, use ‘there is’\n\n-Negative:\n\n+ There is/there are + no + noun\n\n+There is/there are + not + any",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Were there many trees in the park? No, there _____.",
      "a": "hadn't",
      "b": "wasn't",
      "c": "weren't",
      "d": "were no",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "- There is (= have): used when object is singular or uncountable noun\n- There are (= have): used when object is plural noun\n- Negative form: there isn't/ aren't+ object?\n- Past simple : there is -> there was; there are -> there were",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "There ______ any electricity in our village ten years ago.",
      "a": "isn't",
      "b": "weren't",
      "c": "wasn't",
      "d": "hasn't been",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "-Use the Simple Past:\n+To express the idea that an action started and finished at a specific time in the past.\n+Signal words: yesterday, last week, last year, ago, in (+ period of time in the past), when (when I was young, when I was small...)\n- \"Electricity\" is a uncountable noun.\n- There is/ there are: used to say that something exists or happens\n+There is/was/has been + singular noun/uncountable noun\n+ There are/were/have been + plural countable noun",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "I wish there _______ some coputers and stereos in the school.",
      "a": "was",
      "b": "are",
      "c": "were",
      "d": "wasn't",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "There are three distinct types of I wish / if only sentences:\n1/ Wish, wanting change for the present or future with the simple past.\n2/ Regret with the past perfect.\n3/ Complaints with would + verb.\n-Wish + past simple: subject + wish + subject + past simple tense\n+You can use wish + past simple to show that you are not satisfied with a situation in the present.\n+The past tense is used to show that what you wish is not real - it is the opposite of the real situation\n- There is/ there are: used to say that something exists or happens\n+When the following noun is plural, use there are/were (some coputers and stereos )\n+When the following noun is singular use there is/was",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "There _______ a bed, a desk and a cchair in his room.",
      "a": "is",
      "b": "are",
      "c": "has",
      "d": "have",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "- There is/ there are: used to say that something exists or happens\n+When the following noun is plural, use there are/were/have been",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "There ______ four chairs and a table in the living room.",
      "a": "is",
      "b": "are",
      "c": "has",
      "d": "have",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "- There is/ there are: used to say that something exists or happens\n+When the following noun is plural, use 'there are'\n+When the following noun is singular countable/uncountable, use 'there is'",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "10",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    }
  ]
}